Guide to the Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst papers, 1887-1978.
Elmhirst, Dorothy Whitney Straight papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst papers, 1887-1978, 1887-1926 (bulk)
3725
Dorothy Payne Whitney Straight Elmhirst
10 cubic ft.
Correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs, clippings, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes both sides of Dorothy's correspondence with Willard D. Straight; letters from friends and relatives. Also materials on civic activities, correspondence on Willard Straight Hall, and correspondence on The New Republic and Asia magazines.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Philanthropist, educator, publisher, patron of the arts and social activist.
Dorothy Payne Whitney, daughter of William C. Whitney, married Willard Dickerman Straight in 1911. Straight died in 1919, and she married Leonard Knight Elmhirst in 1925.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes both sides of Dorothy's correspondence with Willard D. Straight; letters from friends, and from her sister-in-law Gertrude V. Whitney and other relatives.
Also notebooks, guardianship papers, newspaper clippings, guest books and photographs documenting her early life; correspondence, newspaper clippings, and certificates for her civic activities; communications about Willard Straight's death and funeral arrangements, his will and photographs; correspondence about the building of Willard Straight Hall at Cornell University, and correspondence on The New Republic and Asia magazines. Major correspondents include Beatrice Bend (later Mrs. Henry Prather Fletcher), Katharine L. Barney (later Mrs. Courtlandt D. Barnes), Maurice Casenave, Herbert and Louise Croly, James Curtis, Henry P. Davison, William A. Delano, Richard Derby, Margaret (Myra) G. Dix (later Mrs. Charles Lawrance), Martin Egan, Alfred W. Fiedler, Henry Prather Fletcher, Florence (Daisy) Jaffray Harriman, Louise (Tottie) R. Knowlton (later Mrs. Buell Hollister), and George D. Marvin.
Also, William and Caroline D. Phillips, Ethel C. Roosevelt (later Mrs. Richard Derby), Susan R. Sedgwick (widow of Arthur Swann, later Mrs. Paul L. Hammond), Hazel Straight (later Mrs. James Forest Sanborn), Eliza Morgan Swift, May Tuckerman (later Mrs. Hermann Kinnicutt), Pauline P. Whitney (later Mrs. Almeric H. Paget), Anna L.B. Williams, and Gladys M. Vanderbilt (later Countess Szechenyi), A. Piatt Andrew, J. Howland Auchincloss, Robert and Martha W. Bacon and their son Robert Low Bacon, Frances P.B. Bolton, William J. Calhoun, Wilbur R. Chenoweth, Winston Churchill, Ellen Straight Cross, Richard Harding Davis, Charles D. Draper, Lord Charles French, John Foord, Mary Harriman (later Mrs. Charles C. Rumsey), Herbert C. Hoover, Colonel Edward M. House, Delancey K. Jay, Walter Lippmann, Charles Merz, Ruth Morgan, Annah D. Ripley (later Countess de Viel Castel), Alice L. Roosevelt (later Mrs. Nicholas Longworth), Corinne Roosevelt (later Mrs. Douglas Robinson), Theodore Roosevelt, Elihu Root, Lillian Wald, Lloyd Warren, William Fitz Hugh (Sheldon) Whitehouse, and Stark Young.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Elmhirst, Dorothy Payne Whitney Straight.; Andrew, A. Piatt(Abram Piatt), 1873-1936.; Auchincloss, J. Howland.; Bacon, Martha W.; Bacon, Robert Law.; Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919.; Barney, Katharine L.; Bend, Beatrice.; Bolton, Frances P. B.; Calhoun, William J.; Casenave, Maurice.; Chenoweth, Wilbur R.; Churchill, Winston, 1871-1947.; Croly, Herbert David.; Croly, Louise.; Cross, Ellen Straight.; Curtis, James.; Davis, Richard Harding, 1864-1916.; Davison, Henry P.; Delano, William A.; Derby, Ethel Roosevelt.; Derby, Richard.; Dix, Margaret G.; Draper, Charles D.; Egan, Martin.; Elmhirst, L. K.(Leonard Knight), 1893-1974.; French, Charles,; Fiedler, Alfred W.; Fletcher, Henry Prather.; Foord, John.; Harriman, Florence Jaffray.; Harriman, Mary.; Hoover, Herbert(Herbert Clark), 1874-1964.; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938.; Jay, Delancey K.; Knowlton, Louise R.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1884-1980.; Marvin, George D.; Merz, Charles.; Morgan, Ruth.; Phillips, Caroline D.; Phillips, William.; Ripley, Annah D.; Roosevelt, Corinne.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Sedgwick, Susan R.; Straight, Hazel.; Straight, Willard Dickerman, 1880-1918.; Swift, Eliza Morgan.; Tuckerman, May.; Vanderbilt, Gladys M.; Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940.; Warren, Lloyd.; Whitehouse, William Fitz Hugh.; Whitney, Gertrude Vanderbilt, 1877-1942.; Whitney, Pauline P.; Williams, Anna L. B.; Young, Stark, 1881-1963.; Bordentown Military Academy.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Hobart College.; Junior League.; Mayor's Committee of Women on National Defense.; New School for Social Research.; New York State Food Commission.; Pueblos Defense Committee.; Social Unit Plan.; Tuberculosis Preventorium for Children.; War Camp Service Committee.; Willard Straight Hall (Ithaca, N.Y.); Women's Emergency Committee of the European Relief Council.; Women's Liberty Loan Committee.
Titles:
New republic.
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918.; Social reformers.; Women social reformers.
Places:
Asia.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Portions of this collection are available on microfilm. The guide to the microfilm is here.
NOTES
Related collection:Willard Dickerman Straight. Papers, #1260.
Related collection:Dorothy Whitney Straight. Papers from Dartington Hall, #3782.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-4, 13. Reels 1-10
Willard D. Straight to Dorothy Whitney Straight
Willard D. Straight to Others
Others to Dorothy Whitney Straight
Engagement and wedding congratulations, 1911
Congratulations on Whitney W. Straight's birth, 1912
Dorothy to Willard
Dorothy to Others
Others to Willard
Wedding congratulations (to Leonard K. Elmhirst), 1925
Transcripts of Correspondence (not microfilmed or indexed)
Series II. Other papers through 1911
Boxes 5-7, 9. Reels 11, 12
Photographs, documents, miscellany
Notes
Series III. Other papers, 1912 through 1925
Boxes 8-10. Reels 12-14
1130 Fifth Avenue
Civic activities
Willard D. Straight in France, 1917-1918 (see also #1260, reel 7)
India House
Asia magazine
Willard Straight Hall
Series IV. The New Republic
Boxes 11-12. Reels 14-16
Correspondence
Accounts
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  Also available on microfilm reels 1-10.
  - Willard D. Straight to Dorothy Whitney Straight
    - Sept. 4, 1909 - Oct. 20, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Nov. 2, 1909 - Nov. 29, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dec. 7, 1909 - Dec. 25, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Jan. 1, 1910 - Jan. 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Feb. 1, 1910 - Feb. 23, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mar. 6, 1910 - Mar. 30, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Apr. 2, 1910 - Apr. 30, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - May 10, 1910 - May 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - June 2, 1910 - June 20, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - June 21, 1910 - June 27, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - July 2, 1910 - July 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - July 22, 1910 - July 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Aug. 1, 1910 - Aug. 12, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Aug. 13, 1910 - Aug. 23, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Aug. 24, 1910 - Aug. 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sept. 1, 1910 - Sept. 10, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Sept. 12, 1910 - Sept. 26, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Oct. 8, 1910 - Oct. 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Nov. 4, 1910 - Nov. 13, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Nov. 16, 1910 - Nov. 30, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dec. 1, 1910 - Dec. 20, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dec. 21, 1910 - Dec. 31, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - May 25, 1910 - Nov. 2, 1910 (cable code) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Jan. 1, 1911 - Jan. 15, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Jan. 16, 1911 - Jan. 29, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Feb. 2, 1911 - Feb. 15, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Feb. 16, 1911 - Feb. 28, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Mar. 1, 1911 - Mar. 29, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Apr. 2, 1911 - Apr. 29, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - May 1, 1911 - May 28, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - June 3, 1911 - June 24, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - July 6, 1911 - July 31, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - July 1911 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Aug. 1, 1911 - Aug. 6, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Aug. 7, 1911 - Aug. 31, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Sept. 1, 1911 - Nov. 1911 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Jan. 23, 1912 - July 16, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Aug. 8, 1912 - Nov. 26, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - June 25, 1913 - Oct. 10, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Sept. 9, 1914 - Oct. 27, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Dec. 7, 1914- Dec. 21, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Dec. 22, 1914 - Dec. 31, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Jan. 1, 1915 - Mar. 19, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - May 26, 1915 - Sept. 3, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Mar. 11, 1916 - Apr. 6, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Apr. 7, 1916 - May 13, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - July 27, 1916 - Sept. 8, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Jan. 2, 1917 - Sept. 9, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Sept. 13, 1917 - Sept. 30, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Oct. 1, 1917 - Nov. 7, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Dec. 10, 1917 - Dec. 31, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Dec. 25, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Jan. 2, 1918 - Feb. 26, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Mar. 2, 1918 - Apr. 30, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - May 7, 1918 - June 2, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - June 3, 1918 - June 30, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - July 1, 1918 - Aug. 2, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Aug. 3, 1918 - Sept. 1, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Sept. 2, 1918 - Oct. 7, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Oct. 7, 1918 - Nov. 17, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Willard D. Straight to Others
    - June 23, 1911 - May 13, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sept. 11, 1910 - July 4, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dec. 10, 1917 - Dec. 11, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dec. 15, 1901- July 22, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Others to Dorothy Whitney Straight
    - Feb. 6, 1904 - June 28, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - July 30, 1904 - Dec. 1, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Jan. 10, 1904 - Mar. 28, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Apr. 4, 1905 - Dec. 14, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Feb. 28, 1906 - June 27, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - July 3, 1906 - July 26, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Aug. 1, 1906 - Aug. 31, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sept. 1, 1906 - Dec. 26, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Jan. 14, 1907 - Apr. 23, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - May 8, 1907 - Dec. 3, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Jan. 23, 1908 - Dec. 26, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Jan 3, 1909 - Dec. 26, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Jan 8, 1910 - July 23, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Aug. 8, 1910 - Dec. 30, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Oct. 30, 1910 - Apr. 26, 1911, A. Piatt Andrew (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Jan. 2, 1911 - Dec. 31, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Jan. 24, 1912 - Dec. 13, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Jan 17, 1914 - Dec. 21, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Feb. 7, 1916 - Dec. 29, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Feb. 15, 1918 - Dec. 12, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1918, Flower cards for WDS's funeral (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Jan. 16, 1919 - Aug. 21, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Aug. 23, 1919 - Nov. 28, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mar. 4, 1920 - Dec. 30, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Jan. 5, 1921 - Dec. 27, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Feb. 15, 1922 - Dec. 6, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Jan. 25, 1923 - Nov. 30, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Jan. 22, 1924 - July 7, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Oct. 26, 1910 - Sept. 15, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - July 4, 1923 - Dec. 12, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 1904-1907 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 1908-1911; Nov. 16, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1906-1925 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - June 2, 1918 - Apr. 16, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 1910, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 1910 - 1918 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Nov. 28, 1910 - Dec. 1, 1924, Roosevelt family to DWS (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - June 12, 1909 - Jan. 1, 1922, Eliza M. Swift to DWS (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - June 22, 1904 - Aug. 8, 1905, May Tuckerman to DWS (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - May 16, 1906 - Dec. 2, 1907, May T. Kinnicutt to DWS (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - June 17, 1908 - 1922, May T. Kinnicutt to DWS (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - June 16, 1909 - Mar. 2, 1922, Lillian D. Wald to DWS (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Mar. 3, 1911 - May 10, 1924, Stark Young to DWS (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - 1916, Condolence, Pauline's death (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - 1918, Condolence - Willard's death (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Engagement and wedding congratulations, 1911
    - A-B (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - C-E (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - F-G (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - H-J (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Kellogg (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - K-Lawrance (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Lindley-McKnight (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mean-Murphy (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - N-Ripley (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Roosevelt-Spinney (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Steele-T (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Viel Castel-Wendell (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Wheelock-Wright (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Organizations (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Congratulations on Whitney W. Straight's birth, 1912
    - B-H (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - J-W (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dorothy to Willard
    - Nov. 17, 1909 Dec. 29, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jan. 23, 1910 - Mar. 20, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Apr. 12, 1910 - May 31, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - June 2, 1910 - June 29, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - July 5, 1910 - Aug. 31, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Sept. 4, 1910- Sept. 29, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Oct. 8, 1910 - Nov. 25, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 1, 1910 - Dec. 28, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Jan. 4, 1910 - Jan. 31, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mar. 5, 1911 - Feb. 28, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Mar. 5, 1911 - Apr. 28, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - May 21, 1911 - June 20, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - July 13, 1911 - July 31, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Aug. 1, 1911 - Aug. 30, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Sept. 1, 1911 - Dec. 31, 1911 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Apr. 23, 1912 - June 19, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Aug. 20, 1912 - June 19, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - June 25, 1912 - Nov. 8, 1913 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - June 21, 1914 - Dec. 29, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Jan. 1, 1915 - May 27, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - July 14, 1915 - Sept. 4, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mar. 17, 1916 - May 19, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Jan. 25, 1917 - July 19, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Sept. 5, 1917 - Sept. 30, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Oct. 2, 1917 - Oct. 19, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Dec. 15, 1917 - Dec. 30, 1917 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Jan. 1, 1918 - Jan. 31, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Feb. 6, 1918 - Mar. 31, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Apr. 4, 1918 - Apr. 24, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - May 4, 1918 - May 30, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - June 5, 1918 - June 26, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - July 4, 1918 - July 25, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Aug. 1, 1918 - Aug. 19, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Aug. 22, 1918 - Sept. 3, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Sept. 7, 1918 - Sept. 29, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Oct. 6, 1918 - Nov. 5, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Nov. 15, 1918 - Nov. 17, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Dorothy to Others
    - Nov. 18, 1909 - July 24, 1911 [Katherine L. Barnes] (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 1904, 1909, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Others to Willard
    - Mar. 1, 1910 - Aug. 1, 1911 [Beatrice Bend] (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Mar. 21, 1910 - Aug. 20, 1910 [John O. P. Bland] (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Oct. 10, 1910 - July 26, 1917 [Henry P. Fletcher] (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - 1910 - 1911 and n.d. [Margaret D. Lawrence] (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - 1910-1911 [George D. Marvin] (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - 1910 [Pauline P. Paget] (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - 1916-1918 [Straight children] (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - 1910-1913, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 1910-1924 [B-H] (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - 1909-1911 [J-M] (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - 1910-1917 [N-S] (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - 1909-1916 [T-Y] (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - July 9, 1910 - Feb. 15, 1918 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Oct. 15, 1910 - Nov. 8, 1912 [Peter Bowditch] (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Wedding congratulations (to Leonard K. Elmhirst), 1925
    - 1925 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Transcripts of Correspondence (not microfilmed or indexed)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Nov. 2, 1909 - May 27, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Willard to Dorothy, June 15, 1910 - Sept. 26, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Nov. 5, 1910 - Dec. 31, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Jan. 1, 1911 - Feb. 13, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Feb. 15, 1911 - Mar. 29, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Apr. 2, 1911 - Aug. 11, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Willard to Dorothy, May 30, 1918 - Sept. 30, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Willard to Dorothy, Oct. 1, 1918 - Dec. 10, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Dorothy to Beatrice Bend, Oct. 29, 1911 - Nov. 30, 1911, Jan. 9, 1912 - Jan. 19, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Willard to others, Feb. 15, 1910 - Apr. 24, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Series II. Other papers through 1911
  Also available on microfilm reels 11-12.
  - Photographs, documents, miscellany
    - Notebooks (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
    - Reprint, "A Gallant Lady"; correspondence concerning Flora P. Whitney biography - Mark Hirsh (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Photos and newspaper clippings concerning W. C. Whitney, Old Westbury, Long Island (pre-1904) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings concerning W. C. Whitney's death (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Account of Harry P. Whitney, Dorothy's Testamentary Guardian, 1904-1908 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Guardianship papers, 1909-1910 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Photos of Dorothy and friends (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Guestbook, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1906-1911 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Notes and clippings, Yale Junior Prom, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Aiken, South Carolina and W. C. Whitney's houses in Westbury, Long Island and New York City (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Photos of house of Mr. and Mrs. Henry B. Payne, parents of Flora P. Whitney, Dorothy's mother (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Home of George Washington, Mount Vernon - photo (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Dorothy's trip to Europe, 1904 - mounted photos (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Photos of Dorothy and friends through 1911 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Wedding photo, 1911, Geneva (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Photo album, 1905-1909 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Honeymoon scrapbook, 1911-1912 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Available by appointment only.
  - Notes
    - Notes, no date (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Notes, 1905, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series III. Other papers, 1912-1925
  Also available on microfilm reels 12-14.
  - 1130 Fifth Avenue
    - Residence budget, miscellany (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - World War I menu with recipes (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Recipes (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Inventory list of furnishings (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Accession Books I & II (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Civic activities
    - Correspondence, newspaper clippings, documents (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Photos 1912-1925 (including wedding photo of Dorothy Whitney to Leonard K. Elmhirst) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook, 1917-1919 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1912-1926 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, 1912-1918 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Maps: New York, Long Island (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Photo, 1917 (Wedding, Beatrice Bend - Henry Prather Fletcher) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Willard D. Straight in France, 1917-1918 (see also #1260, reel 7)
    - Appointment as Major of the infantry, July 9, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Handwritten copies of cables sent and received by Dorothy during and after Willard's illness (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Cable exchnage relating to Willard's illness and death (Nov. 25, 1918 - Dec. 1, 1918) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and photos relating to "Suresnes American Cemetary and Memorial" (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - WDS's last Will (two copies), filed 1919 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - India House
    - Receipts, 1914-1918 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1914, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Members and by-laws, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Financial records, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Financial records, 1916-1917 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Financial records, 1920, 1921, 1925 (including documents relating to sale) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Asia magazine
    - Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1920 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Minutes, miscellany, 1915-1924 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Constitution, 1914, report on audit, 1920, 1922, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Willard Straight Hall
    - Correspondence, 1922-1925 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Other student unions, pamphlets, reports (Box 10, Folder 1 & 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1922-1925 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Blueprints (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence concerning Cornerstone ceremony, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photo album (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Photo album, Willard Straight Hall (being built) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series IV. The New Republic
  Also available on microfilm reels 14-16.
  - Correspondence
    - 1914 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1915 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1916 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 1917 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 1918 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1921 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - 1922 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 1923 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 1924 (January-July) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 1924 (August-December) (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - 1925 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - 1915-1917 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Accounts
    - Financial Records, 1915-1925 (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
    - Financial Correspondence, 1915-1925 (Box 12, Folder 9-14)